<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>flat patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/flat-patternmaking/</link><description>Recent content in flat patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/flat-patternmaking/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry, click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young and fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;,I wait for a couple of days—and that’s a challenging process—and if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that’s it, I’m going to sew it.</description></item></channel></rss>