<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/rss.xml</link><description>Recent content on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>04. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Pivotal Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</guid><description>In the previous post, we learned what common dart designs are and how to create them with a slash method. This method builds an excellent base for understanding the patternmaking process and future manipulations. So, if you missed that post, I advise reading it first because this article is a direct extension of it.
Today we will work with the same two-dart designs as last time, but we’ll use a pivotal method to make the patterns.</description></item><item><title>How to Sew a Crew Neckband for a T-shirt</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-t-shirt-crew-neckband/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-t-shirt-crew-neckband/</guid><description>This tutorial is a complementary post for Jane: Boxy Crewneck T-shirt pattern which I currently release for free.
The Prologue Cruising through currants of so-alike-but-yet-different manufactured T-shirts, I could never find a perfect one for years. Scrolling from time to time through “Best 20 T-shirts to buy in 20.. (insert the year)”, I hoped I would find that matching tee for the skirt, which is lonely hanging in the closet.</description></item><item><title>Jane: Boxy Crewneck T-shirt. Free Sewing Pattern</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/jane-pattern-boxy-t-shirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/jane-pattern-boxy-t-shirt/</guid><description>Current status of the pattern: Free for release by request.
The Prologue “From humble origins as an undergarment to mass-produced fast-fashion staple to highly collectible (and highly priced) commodity, the white T-shirt is a quintessential product of twentieth-century modernity and the ultimate sartorial and psychological blank canvas.”
Antonelli Paola, Millar Fisher Michelle. ITEMS: Is Fashion Modern?. New York: The Museum of Modern Art, 2017.
In its exhibition, the Museum of Modern Art included a white T-shirt into a list of 111 garments that massively influenced both fashion and the whole world during its history.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sewing Pattern Adjustments</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/basic-pattern-adjustments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/basic-pattern-adjustments/</guid><description>This tutorial is a complementary post for Jane: Boxy Crewneck T-shirt pattern which I currently release for free.
We all are different, and we all are beautiful. So alike in a general overview, but entirely different in details. Every feature in us makes us unique. This uniqueness means there is no single size chart or pattern that will perfectly fit everyone. And it’s okay because by choosing the closest suitable size and making a couple of adjustments to a standard pattern, you can get that desired fit.</description></item><item><title>Store and Fabrics Review: Atelier Brunette</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/atelier-brunette-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/atelier-brunette-review/</guid><description>This post is not sponsored. No matter how delighted I might seem. It is not.
You can find links to stores &amp;amp; fabrics mentioned here at the end of this article. Though that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should jump right there.
The Prologue While most of the stores selling non-essential goods remain closed in Germany and the majority of people staying in their homes, it is no wonder that e-commerce was experiencing a rise in 2020.</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item><item><title>How to Sew a Bow Collar for a Blouse</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</guid><description>Bow collars pop up in the first row of a fashion scene relatively often. They are loved and presented by luxury brands like Gucci and Saint Laurent.
I still remember the Gucci &amp;ldquo;Guilty&amp;rdquo; advertisement, which stole my heart forever and Saint Laurent 2020–2021 Autumn–Winter collection with its bow-tie blouses and power-jackets is at the top of my favourites so far.
The bow collar can look modest, but it also may be seductive, revealing that tiny bit of a collarbone.</description></item><item><title>02. Pattern Shapes &amp; Flat Patternmaking</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</guid><description>After learning what block patterns are, let’s take a closer look at a basic dress block and what one needs to know to make other dresses from it.
Pattern Shapes Here you can see a 5-piece basic block for a semi-fitted dress made of non-stretchy woven fabric. There are front and back bodice pieces, front and back skirt pieces and a wrist-length set-in sleeve.
From now on, I’ll be using this set to show different pattern manipulations.</description></item><item><title>01. The Block Patterns</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</guid><description>In the previous introduction post, I briefly wrote about two main stages of patternmaking that lead you from an idea to a beautiful dress: the basic block and flat patternmaking. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what the first one is.
Block patterns are the basic shapes which are later transformed into new garment designs.
You might find them not only in the apparel field but in bag, shoes and many other fields, which I know nothing about.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young and fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;,I wait for a couple of days—and that’s a challenging process—and if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that’s it, I’m going to sew it.</description></item><item><title>The Renovation</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</guid><description>The Prologue It’s been a really long time since I wrote the last post here. I can’t even remember when and what it was. It’s not like I had nothing to say, I just guess I’m not the person who can tell a whole novel about going to a grocery shop. But sometimes projects or events, that are worth mentioning, happen. That’s why there are times of stillness here in this Journal.</description></item><item><title>Bows &amp; Flowers. Illustrating Sewing Plans</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/bows-and-flowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/bows-and-flowers/</guid><description>While my dress form is still drying, I had some time to illustrate my sewing plans.
Prologue A magical commercial or I’d better say, a short-film by Gucci inspired me to draw a couple of illustrations. That film tells a story about a man and two girls, who spend their time in mystic and foggy Venice. The city is empty, everything is blurred and tainted with gold and foggy grey colours.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 2. Techniques for Sewing</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</guid><description>There are no certain rules for every exact lace because everything depends on the tread type, the background and overall quality, but there are some common guides for all laces.
Pattern choice When choosing the pattern and design let the fabric determine what it’ll be like. Don’t pull and force it or cut it into multiple pattern pieces, that can destroy the motifs. Let the fabric show its beauty.
For laconiс fitted silhouettes use heavy laces like Alencon and Cluny.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 1. History &amp; Types</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</guid><description>Prologue I bought the pansies-strewn fabric impulsively without a clear idea, just because I liked it, and hadn’t worked with lace before. For the last reason, the fabric safely lay in the box for another year. Once a couple of months I took it out, chaotically draped on myself and without the desired result put it back. I knew it would be a dress, but what dress – that was the question.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 2. The Plaster Mold</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</guid><description>When the praparation with all the materials, a place and a right pose for my future dress form was done, we were ready to get to the point.
We’ve decided, that the final plaster mould would consist of two layers: one horizontal and one vertical. Each layer would be made of 3 layers of plaster bandage. So, it will be 6 layers thick. This will make the mould firm enough to keep the shape and not get wet with moisture from papier-mache.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 1. The Beginning</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</guid><description>One year and five months I’ve spent deciding which tailor’s dummy to buy. I saw it in my dreams, it tormented me by thoughts of the tops of draping, which I could conquer with it. The discrepancy between the desired and affordable option drove me into a week of melancholy.
The Options Time had passed, and I was still rushing from one option to another. I chose between a soft substandard dummy with short legs for a relatively adequate price and a firm one with a skirt and the shipping price, that cost as much as the dummy itself.</description></item><item><title>One More Kimono &amp; a Tulip Sleeve</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</guid><description>Curious faces peer over my shoulder and ask what I am sewing: a silk robe or a negligee. I hear this question for the hundredth time. So I breathe out quietly in a meditative manner and with a mysterious smile, I answer that I’m sewing neither one nor the other.
After all, I know that in a dozen stitches I will finish the bohemian kimono, which I have wanted for many years.</description></item><item><title>Fashion Illustration in Design Process</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</guid><description>Imagination takes you to distant cities, introduces to people from other continents and dresses you up in clothes that you have never worn before. If building a new city is problematic, and it is sometimes impossible to find strangers from the dream, sewing a dress is easy.
The main thing is to correctly translate the thought from the head to the fabric. I imagine this process as travelling by train from one city to another.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post I wrote about the difference between interfacing and interlining. There I described the fabrics and techniques I used to give this coat shape and support.
And now my hands are burning, because it&amp;rsquo;s time to draw a pattern for the inner structure.
The Interfacing Patterns I do not print the details of the inner structure in advance, so I place tracing paper on top of the pattern and draw new contours.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</guid><description>As soon as snow covers the streets, I start to feel an uncontrollable desire to warm myself with at least one new sweater. Every time I finish a new knitted something, I swear to never touch the needles again. And every time, as soon as it becomes cold and dark, I start ordering yarn. I need a sweater, and a hat and a scarf, and a sweater, yes, it will be warmer.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 3.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-3/</guid><description>This is the final and the shortest part of my yet longest trilogy.
If you’ve just joined, feel free to start with Part 1, which tells about inspiration and preparatory process, and Part 2 – there you can read about patterns and samples.
Let’s continue.
7. Cutting the fashion fabric Well-done cutting also needs some rules:
The fabric needs pre-shrinking with heat or water beforehand, so that after the first wash the M-size blouse won’t unexpectedly turn into XXS.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</guid><description>If you’ve just joined the reading, please, visit the first part page. It tells about inspiration, ideas, ways of getting a pattern and measurements. If you please, I’ll continue.
4. Pattern A pattern is the template, the blueprint, from which the parts of a garment—like sleeves, front and back bodice, collar, etc.—are placed and traced onto fabric before being cut out and assembled. Patterns may be drafted manually or digitally.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</guid><description>For the first half of my sewing life, I was using ready-made patterns. Unexpectedly, the choice that the magazines provided was not enough, and the decision to create a dress from the beginning to the end came by itself. This was the beginning of a new era.
At that moment, I was left alone with my knowledge, skills and a million doubts. There was nothing that could help, no trued pattern, no step-by-step instructions, or even a brief scheme.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-2/</guid><description>As I promised in the mysterious pre-story, here are more process details, hundreds of hand stitches and meters of bias binding hidden behind the ruffles.
The first part of this story tells about the idea, that evolved into this beautiful skirt, its patternmaking process and cutting. So, if you missed it, please, click a link above.
Be my guest and enjoy.
Attaching the Interlining For interlining I choose the cambric, which, for some unknown reason, already lied in the closet.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</guid><description>October 2016.
“Stripes are always in fashion, but now especially aggressive ones. Horizontal and vertical at the same time, wide and narrow in super-bright colours.“
Wrote the Vogue magazine on top of the vivid photos from the shows of Fendi, Miu Miu, Proenza Schouler in an article about the fashion trends of the upcoming 2017 year.
Snow is already falling in the morning, the sun gently shines through the window and it’s cold.</description></item><item><title>Confirm Your Subscription</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/confirm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/confirm/</guid><description>Well done! To confirm your subscription, please, check your mailbox for a new email from me and click the verification button. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see the email, take a look at the spam box—unfortunately, an email may get caught there.
xoxo, Kaia</description></item><item><title>Your subscription has been successful</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/subscribed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/subscribed/</guid><description>Yay! Now I can send you notifications about all the lovely blog and pattern updates that are coming. Please, make sure the emails don&amp;rsquo;t get stuck in the spam box. And do not worry; I will not spam your mailbox—I do not write that fast.
Thank you for joining my newsletter.
xoxo, Kaia</description></item><item><title>Your un-subscription has been successful</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/unsubscribed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/newsletter/unsubscribed/</guid><description>From now on, you will no longer receive emails from me. It is a bit sad to see us part our ways. And I want you to know; you are welcome to come back anytime.
Thank you for staying with &amp;ldquo;Dressed in a Dress&amp;rdquo;.
xoxo, Kaia</description></item><item><title>Work With Me</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/work-with-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:29:39 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/work-with-me/</guid><description>Well, hello So, what are you? I am Kaia Meier, and I am a graphics girl and technical illustrator. I create graphic content for sewing patterns’ instructions and draw fashion and technical flats and layouts. Most of the time, I work with womenswear.
What can you help me with? If you already have a sewing-pattern brand or start one or write a book on sewing techniques, I can help with the graphical part.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/about-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/about-me/</guid><description>Hello, I am Kaia Meier, an illustrator, passionate sewer and the author of this journal.
Do you know those pretty illustrations that guide you through the sewing process step by step? “Sew it this way, press it that way”, that’s what I draft during work hours. Oh wait, I used to do that during my free time too because I tried to create my sewing-pattern brand. At this moment, it didn’t work out, but I am not sad because I love what I do.</description></item></channel></rss>