<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fabrics on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/fabrics/</link><description>Recent content in Fabrics on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/fabrics/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Store and Fabrics Review: Atelier Brunette</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/atelier-brunette-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/atelier-brunette-review/</guid><description>This post is not sponsored. No matter how delighted I might seem. It is not.
You can find links to stores &amp;amp; fabrics mentioned here at the end of this article. Though that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should jump right there.
The Prologue While most of the stores selling non-essential goods remain closed in Germany and the majority of people staying in their homes, it is no wonder that e-commerce was experiencing a rise in 2020.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 2. Techniques for Sewing</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</guid><description>There are no certain rules for every exact lace because everything depends on the tread type, the background and overall quality, but there are some common guides for all laces.
Pattern choice When choosing the pattern and design let the fabric determine what it’ll be like. Don’t pull and force it or cut it into multiple pattern pieces, that can destroy the motifs. Let the fabric show its beauty.
For laconiс fitted silhouettes use heavy laces like Alencon and Cluny.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 1. History &amp; Types</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</guid><description>Prologue I bought the pansies-strewn fabric impulsively without a clear idea, just because I liked it, and hadn’t worked with lace before. For the last reason, the fabric safely lay in the box for another year. Once a couple of months I took it out, chaotically draped on myself and without the desired result put it back. I knew it would be a dress, but what dress – that was the question.</description></item></channel></rss>