<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hand-sewing on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/hand-sewing/</link><description>Recent content in hand-sewing on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/hand-sewing/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Sew a Bow Collar for a Blouse</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</guid><description>Bow collars pop up in the first row of a fashion scene relatively often. They are loved and presented by luxury brands like Gucci and Saint Laurent.
I still remember the Gucci &amp;ldquo;Guilty&amp;rdquo; advertisement, which stole my heart forever and Saint Laurent 2020–2021 Autumn–Winter collection with its bow-tie blouses and power-jackets is at the top of my favourites so far.
The bow collar can look modest, but it also may be seductive, revealing that tiny bit of a collarbone.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 2. Techniques for Sewing</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</guid><description>There are no certain rules for every exact lace because everything depends on the tread type, the background and overall quality, but there are some common guides for all laces.
Pattern choice When choosing the pattern and design let the fabric determine what it’ll be like. Don’t pull and force it or cut it into multiple pattern pieces, that can destroy the motifs. Let the fabric show its beauty.
For laconiс fitted silhouettes use heavy laces like Alencon and Cluny.</description></item><item><title>One More Kimono &amp; a Tulip Sleeve</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</guid><description>Curious faces peer over my shoulder and ask what I am sewing: a silk robe or a negligee. I hear this question for the hundredth time. So I breathe out quietly in a meditative manner and with a mysterious smile, I answer that I’m sewing neither one nor the other.
After all, I know that in a dozen stitches I will finish the bohemian kimono, which I have wanted for many years.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post I wrote about the difference between interfacing and interlining. There I described the fabrics and techniques I used to give this coat shape and support.
And now my hands are burning, because it&amp;rsquo;s time to draw a pattern for the inner structure.
The Interfacing Patterns I do not print the details of the inner structure in advance, so I place tracing paper on top of the pattern and draw new contours.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</guid><description>As soon as snow covers the streets, I start to feel an uncontrollable desire to warm myself with at least one new sweater. Every time I finish a new knitted something, I swear to never touch the needles again. And every time, as soon as it becomes cold and dark, I start ordering yarn. I need a sweater, and a hat and a scarf, and a sweater, yes, it will be warmer.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-2/</guid><description>As I promised in the mysterious pre-story, here are more process details, hundreds of hand stitches and meters of bias binding hidden behind the ruffles.
The first part of this story tells about the idea, that evolved into this beautiful skirt, its patternmaking process and cutting. So, if you missed it, please, click a link above.
Be my guest and enjoy.
Attaching the Interlining For interlining I choose the cambric, which, for some unknown reason, already lied in the closet.</description></item></channel></rss>