<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>illustration on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/illustration/</link><description>Recent content in illustration on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/illustration/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bows &amp; Flowers. Illustrating Sewing Plans</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/bows-and-flowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/bows-and-flowers/</guid><description>While my dress form is still drying, I had some time to illustrate my sewing plans.
Prologue A magical commercial or I’d better say, a short-film by Gucci inspired me to draw a couple of illustrations. That film tells a story about a man &amp;amp; two girls, who spend their time in mystic &amp;amp; foggy Venice. The city is empty, everything is blurred &amp;amp; tainted with gold &amp;amp; foggy grey colours.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 1. History &amp; Types</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</guid><description>Prologue I bought the pansies-strewn fabric impulsively without a clear idea, just because I liked it, &amp;amp; hadn’t worked with lace before. For the last reason, the fabric safely lay in the box for another year. Once a couple of months I took it out, chaotically draped on myself &amp;amp; without the desired result put it back. I knew it would be a dress, but what dress – that was the question.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 2. The Plaster Mold</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</guid><description>When the praparation with all the materials, a place &amp;amp; a right pose for my future dress form was done, we were ready to get to the point.
We’ve decided, that the final plaster mould would consist of two layers: one horizontal &amp;amp; one vertical. Each layer would be made of 3 layers of plaster bandage. So, it will be 6 layers thick. This will make the mould firm enough to keep the shape &amp;amp; not get wet with moisture from papier-mache.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 1. The Beginning</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</guid><description>One year &amp;amp; five months I’ve spent deciding which tailor’s dummy to buy. I saw it in my dreams, it tormented me by thoughts of the tops of draping, which I could conquer with it. The discrepancy between the desired &amp;amp; affordable option drove me into a week of melancholy.
The Options Time had passed, &amp;amp; I was still rushing from one option to another. I chose between a soft substandard dummy with short legs for a relatively adequate price &amp;amp; a firm one with a skirt &amp;amp; the shipping price, that cost as much as the dummy itself.</description></item><item><title>Fashion Illustration in Design Process</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</guid><description>Imagination takes you to distant cities, introduces to people from other continents &amp;amp; dresses you up in clothes that you have never worn before. If building a new city is problematic, &amp;amp; it is sometimes impossible to find strangers from the dream, sewing a dress is easy.
The main thing is to correctly translate the thought from the head to the fabric. I imagine this process as travelling by train from one city to another.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</guid><description>For the first half of my sewing life, I was using ready-made patterns. Unexpectedly, the choice that the magazines provided was not enough, &amp;amp; the decision to create a dress from the beginning to the end came by itself. This was the beginning of a new era.
At that moment, I was left alone with my knowledge, skills &amp;amp; a million doubts. There was nothing that could help, no trued pattern, no step-by-step instructions, or even a brief scheme.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</guid><description>October 2016.
“Stripes are always in fashion, but now especially aggressive ones. Horizontal &amp;amp; vertical at the same time, wide &amp;amp; narrow in super-bright colours.“
Wrote the Vogue magazine on top of the vivid photos from the shows of Fendi, Miu Miu, Proenza Schouler in an article about the fashion trends of the upcoming 2017 year.
Snow is already falling in the morning, the sun gently shines through the window &amp;amp; it’s cold.</description></item></channel></rss>