<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patternmaking Series on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/patternmaking-series/</link><description>Recent content in Patternmaking Series on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/patternmaking-series/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>04. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Pivotal Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</guid><description>In the previous post, we learned what common dart designs are and how to create them with a slash method. This method builds an excellent base for understanding the patternmaking process and future manipulations. So, if you missed that post, I advise reading it first because this article is a direct extension of it.
Today we will work with the same two-dart designs as last time, but we’ll use a pivotal method to make the patterns.</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item><item><title>02. Pattern Shapes &amp; Flat Patternmaking</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes--flat-patternmaking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes--flat-patternmaking/</guid><description>After learning what block patterns are, let’s take a closer look at a basic dress block and what one needs to know to make other dresses from it.
Pattern Shapes Here you can see a 5-piece basic block for a semi-fitted dress made of non-stretchy woven fabric. There are front and back bodice pieces, front and back skirt pieces and a wrist-length set-in sleeve.
From now on, I’ll be using this set to show different pattern manipulations.</description></item><item><title>01. The Block Patterns</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</guid><description>In the previous introduction post, I briefly wrote about two main stages of patternmaking that lead you from an idea to a beautiful dress: the basic block and flat patternmaking. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what the first one is.
Block patterns are the basic shapes which are later transformed into new garment designs.
You might find them not only in the apparel field but in bag, shoes and many other fields, which I know nothing about.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young and fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;,I wait for a couple of days—and that’s a challenging process—and if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that’s it, I’m going to sew it.</description></item><item><title>The Renovation</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</guid><description>The Prologue It’s been a really long time since I wrote the last post here. I can’t even remember when and what it was. It’s not like I had nothing to say, I just guess I’m not the person who can tell a whole novel about going to a grocery shop. But sometimes projects or events, that are worth mentioning, happen. That’s why there are times of stillness here in this Journal.</description></item></channel></rss>