<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fabrics on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/tags/fabrics/</link><description>Recent content in fabrics on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v-chmykov.github.io/tags/fabrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 2. Techniques for Sewing</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-2/</guid><description>There are no certain rules for every exact lace because everything depends on the tread type, the background &amp;amp; overall quality, but there are some common guides for all laces.
Pattern choice When choosing the pattern &amp;amp; design let the fabric determine what it’ll be like. Don’t pull &amp;amp; force it or cut it into multiple pattern pieces, that can destroy the motifs. Let the fabric show its beauty.</description></item><item><title>Lace &amp; Embroidered Fabric. Part 1. History &amp; Types</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/lace-and-embroidered-fabric-part-1/</guid><description>Prologue I bought the pansies-strewn fabric impulsively without a clear idea, just because I liked it, and hadn’t worked with lace before. For the last reason, the fabric safely lay in the box for another year. Once a couple of months I took it out, chaotically draped on myself and without the desired result put it back. I knew it would be a dress, but what dress – that was the question.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 2.</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post I wrote about the difference between interfacing &amp;amp; interlining. There I described the fabrics &amp;amp; techniques I used to give this coat shape &amp;amp; support.
And now my hands are burning, because it&amp;rsquo;s time to draw a pattern for the inner structure.
The Interfacing Patterns I do not print the details of the inner structure in advance, so I place tracing paper on top of the pattern and draw new contours.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 1.</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</guid><description>As soon as snow covers the streets, I start to feel an uncontrollable desire to warm myself with at least one new sweater. Every time I finish a new knitted something, I swear to never touch the needles again. And every time, as soon as it becomes cold and dark, I start ordering yarn. I need a sweater, and a hat and a scarf, and a sweater, yes, it will be warmer.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 1.</title><link>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://v-chmykov.github.io/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</guid><description>October 2016.
“Stripes are always in fashion, but now especially aggressive ones.” Horizontal and vertical at the same time, wide and narrow in super-bright colours.“
Wrote the Vogue magazine on top of the vivid photos from the shows of Fendi, Miu Miu, Proenza Schouler in an article about the fashion trends of the upcoming 2017 year.
Snow is already falling in the morning, the sun gently shines through the window &amp;amp; it’s cold.</description></item></channel></rss>