<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dress form on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dress-form/</link><description>Recent content in dress form on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dress-form/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 2. The Plaster Mold.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</guid><description>When the praparation with all the materials, a place &amp;amp; a right pose for my future dress form was done, we were ready to get to the point.
We’ve decided, that the final plaster mould would consist of two layers: one horizontal &amp;amp; one vertical. Each layer would be made of 3 layers of plaster bandage. So, it will be 6 layers thick. This will make the mould firm enough to keep the shape &amp;amp; not get wet with moisture from papier-mache.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 1. The Beginning</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</guid><description>One year and five months I’ve spent deciding which tailor’s dummy to buy. I saw it in my dreams, it tormented me by thoughts of the tops of draping, which I could conquer with it. The discrepancy between the desired and affordable option drove me into a week of melancholy.
The Options Time had passed, and I was still rushing from one option to another. I chose between a soft substandard dummy with short legs for a relatively adequate price and a firm one with a skirt and the shipping price, that cost as much as the dummy itself.</description></item></channel></rss>