<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>slash method on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/slash-method/</link><description>Recent content in slash method on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/slash-method/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>05. Common Dart Manipulations: Single-Dart Designs</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</guid><description>Darts play a crucial role in our garments, providing structural integrity and aesthetic appeal, particularly in fitted and semi-fitted designs. Earlier in this Patternmaking Series, we talked about the core elements of the front bodice: the bust and waist darts. We discussed how and why their location could change and learned about the Slash and Pivotal methods that help achieve various two-dart designs.
To refresh the memories, take a look at the previous posts that tell about dart manipulation in the two-dart designs:</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item></channel></rss>