<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dart manipulation on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dart-manipulation/</link><description>Recent content in dart manipulation on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dart-manipulation/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>05. Common Dart Manipulations: Single-Dart Designs</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</guid><description>Darts play a crucial role in our garments, providing structural integrity and aesthetic appeal, particularly in fitted and semi-fitted designs. Earlier in this Patternmaking Series, we talked about the core elements of the front bodice: the bust and waist darts. We discussed how and why their location could change and learned about the Slash and Pivotal methods that help achieve various two-dart designs.
To refresh the memories, take a look at the previous posts that tell about dart manipulation in the two-dart designs:</description></item><item><title>04. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Pivotal Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</guid><description>Continuing with the patternmaking series, we are ready to delve deeper into dart manipulations using the pivotal method. Building on the concepts explored in the previous post with the slash method, we will now learn about the creative potential of another technique. If you’re new to the series or missed the previous post, I recommend starting there to grasp the foundation for today’s tutorial.
Today, we’ll continue working with the same two-dart designs as before, but this time, we’ll employ the pivotal method to create our patterns.</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item></channel></rss>