<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dart manipulation on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dart-manipulation/</link><description>Recent content in dart manipulation on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/dart-manipulation/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>06. Common Dart Manipulations: Back Waist and Shoulder Darts</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/06-common-dart-manipulations-back-bodice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/06-common-dart-manipulations-back-bodice/</guid><description>Diving deeper into pattern manipulation, we can now focus on the back bodice, where strategic dart placements can transform fit and design. If we think of a basic block dress, the back bodice may seem less inspiring than the front one, but the fact that we don’t see our backs every time we look in the mirror doesn’t mean that this back should be overlooked.
Regarding dart manipulations in the back, there might be fewer options than in the front piece, but there are still various design possibilities that will ensure a proper fit.</description></item><item><title>05. Common Dart Manipulations: Single-Dart Designs</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</guid><description>Darts play a crucial role in our garments, providing structural integrity and aesthetic appeal, particularly in fitted and semi-fitted designs. Earlier in this Patternmaking Series, we talked about the core elements of the front bodice: the bust and waist darts. We discussed how and why their location could change and learned about the Slash and Pivotal methods that help achieve various two-dart designs.
To refresh the memories, take a look at the previous posts that tell about dart manipulation in the two-dart designs:</description></item><item><title>04. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Pivotal Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</guid><description>In the previous post, we learned what common dart designs are and how to create them with a slash method. This method builds an excellent base for understanding the patternmaking process and future manipulations. So, if you missed that post, I advise reading it first because this article is a direct extension of it.
Today we will work with the same two-dart designs as last time, but we’ll use a pivotal method to make the patterns.</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item></channel></rss>