<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/tutorials/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Sew a Sleeve Booster</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-sleeve-booster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-sleeve-booster/</guid><description>Ad: This tutorial is a complementary post for the Lili: Balloon-Sleeve Dress pattern, which is now available for sale on Etsy.
This post is based on the knowledge I gained from the fantastic Claire B. Schaeffer books.
The Prologue No matter how good the pattern or fabric you’re working with is, sometimes the combination of materials and conventional at-home sewing techniques just isn’t enough to hold the desired silhouette.</description></item><item><title>How to Sew a Shirt Collar</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-shirt-collar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-shirt-collar/</guid><description>Ad: This tutorial is a complementary post for the Sienna: Button-Down Blouse pattern, which is now available for sale on Etsy.
The Prologue I didn’t plan to write about collars. The truth is, after spending weeks and months designing, planning, and drowning under the weight of the never-ending tasks that came with the Sienna pattern launch, I didn’t plan to write anything. Not. A single. Line.
Yet months later, I found myself curled up on the couch, lazily flipping through the pages and reluctantly looking for ideas that might someday become a new design on my desk.</description></item><item><title>How to Place Buttons and Buttonholes on the Shirt Front</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/shirt-buttons-and-buttonholes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/shirt-buttons-and-buttonholes/</guid><description>Ad: This tutorial is a complementary post for the Sienna: Button-Down Blouse pattern, which is now available for sale on Etsy.
It is no secret that I tend to write long articles, and this one is no exception. It is lengthy, almost like a book chapter, but filled with detailed information. If you’re here for the first time, I recommend reading it all. However, if you’re returning to refresh your memory, feel free to skip to the section you need using the list below.</description></item><item><title>How to Sew a Crew Neckband for a T-shirt</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-t-shirt-crew-neckband/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-t-shirt-crew-neckband/</guid><description>This tutorial is a complementary post for Jane: Boxy Crewneck T-shirt pattern which I currently release for free.
The Prologue Cruising through currants of so-alike-but-yet-different manufactured T-shirts, I could never find a perfect one for years. Scrolling from time to time through “Best 20 T-shirts to buy in 20.. (insert the year)”, I hoped I would find that matching tee for the skirt, which is lonely hanging in the closet.</description></item><item><title>Basic Sewing Pattern Adjustments</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/basic-pattern-adjustments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/basic-pattern-adjustments/</guid><description>This tutorial is a complementary post for Jane: Boxy Crewneck T-shirt pattern which I currently release for free.
We all are different, and we all are beautiful. So alike in a general overview, but entirely different in details. Every feature in us makes us unique. This uniqueness means there is no single size chart or pattern that will perfectly fit everyone. And it’s okay because by choosing the closest suitable size and making a couple of adjustments to a standard pattern, you can get that desired fit.</description></item><item><title>How to Sew a Bow Collar for a Blouse</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/sewing-a-bow-collar/</guid><description>Bow collars pop up in the first row of a fashion scene relatively often. They are loved and presented by luxury brands like Gucci and Saint Laurent.
I still remember the Gucci &amp;ldquo;Guilty&amp;rdquo; advertisement, which stole my heart forever and Saint Laurent 2020–2021 Autumn–Winter collection with its bow-tie blouses and power-jackets is at the top of my favourites so far.
The bow collar can look modest, but it also may be seductive, revealing that tiny bit of a collarbone.</description></item></channel></rss>