<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>series on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/series/</link><description>Recent content in series on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>02. Pattern Shapes &amp; Flat Patternmaking</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</guid><description>After learning what Block Patterns are let’s take a closer look at a Basic Dress Block &amp;amp; what one needs to learn to transform it into other dresses.
Pattern Shapes Here you can see a 5-piece Basic Block for a semi-fitted dress made of non-stretchy woven fabric. There are Front &amp;amp; Back Bodice pieces, Front &amp;amp; Back skirt pieces &amp;amp; a wrist-length set-in sleeve.
From now on I’ll be using this set to show different pattern manipulations.</description></item><item><title>01. The Block Patterns</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</guid><description>In the previous introduction post, I briefly wrote about two main stages of patternmaking that lead you from an idea to a beautiful dress: the Basic Block &amp;amp; Flat Patternmaking. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what the first one is.
Block Patterns are the basic shapes which are later transformed into new garment designs.
You might find them not only in the apparel field but in bag, shoes &amp;amp; many other fields, which I know nothing about.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young &amp;amp; fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;, I wait for a couple of days - and that&amp;rsquo;s a really hard process - and if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that&amp;rsquo;s it, I&amp;rsquo;m going to sew it.</description></item><item><title>The Renovation</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/the-renovation/</guid><description>The Prologue It’s been a really long time since I wrote the last post here. I can’t even remember when &amp;amp; what it was. It’s not like I had nothing to say, I just guess I’m not the person who can tell a whole novel about going to a grocery shop. But sometimes projects or events, that are worth mentioning, happen. That’s why there are times of stillness here in this Journal.</description></item></channel></rss>