<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/patternmaking/</link><description>Recent content in patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/patternmaking/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>02. Pattern Shapes &amp; bust point</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</guid><description>After learning what block patterns are, let’s take a closer look at a basic dress block &amp;amp; what one needs to know to make other dresses from it.
Pattern Shapes Here you can see a 5-piece basic block for a semi-fitted dress made of non-stretchy woven fabric. There are front &amp;amp; back bodice pieces, front &amp;amp; back skirt pieces &amp;amp; a wrist-length set-in sleeve.
From now on, I’ll be using this set to show different pattern manipulations.</description></item><item><title>01. The Block Patterns</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</guid><description>In the previous introduction post, I briefly wrote about two main stages of patternmaking that lead you from an idea to a beautiful dress: the basic block &amp;amp; flat patternmaking. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what the first one is.
Block patterns are the basic shapes which are later transformed into new garment designs.
You might find them not only in the apparel field but in bag, shoes &amp;amp; many other fields, which I know nothing about.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young &amp;amp; fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;,I wait for a couple of days—&amp;amp; that’s a challenging process—&amp;amp; if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that’s it, I’m going to sew it.</description></item><item><title>One More Kimono &amp; a Tulip Sleeve</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</guid><description>Curious faces peer over my shoulder &amp;amp; ask what I am sewing: a silk robe or a negligee. I hear this question for the hundredth time. So I breathe out quietly in a meditative manner &amp;amp; with a mysterious smile, I answer that I’m sewing neither one nor the other.
After all, I know that in a dozen stitches I will finish the bohemian kimono, which I have wanted for many years.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post I wrote about the difference between interfacing &amp;amp; interlining. There I described the fabrics &amp;amp; techniques I used to give this coat shape &amp;amp; support.
And now my hands are burning, because it&amp;rsquo;s time to draw a pattern for the inner structure.
The Interfacing Patterns I do not print the details of the inner structure in advance, so I place tracing paper on top of the pattern &amp;amp; draw new contours.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</guid><description>As soon as snow covers the streets, I start to feel an uncontrollable desire to warm myself with at least one new sweater. Every time I finish a new knitted something, I swear to never touch the needles again. And every time, as soon as it becomes cold &amp;amp; dark, I start ordering yarn. I need a sweater, &amp;amp; a hat &amp;amp; a scarf, &amp;amp; a sweater, yes, it will be warmer.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</guid><description>If you’ve just joined the reading, please, visit the first part page. It tells about inspiration, ideas, ways of getting a pattern &amp;amp; measurements. If you please, I’ll continue.
4. Pattern A pattern is the template, the blueprint, from which the parts of a garment—like sleeves, front &amp;amp; back bodice, collar, etc.—are placed &amp;amp; traced onto fabric before being cut out &amp;amp; assembled. Patterns may be drafted manually or digitally.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</guid><description>For the first half of my sewing life, I was using ready-made patterns. Unexpectedly, the choice that the magazines provided was not enough, &amp;amp; the decision to create a dress from the beginning to the end came by itself. This was the beginning of a new era.
At that moment, I was left alone with my knowledge, skills &amp;amp; a million doubts. There was nothing that could help, no trued pattern, no step-by-step instructions, or even a brief scheme.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</guid><description>October 2016.
“Stripes are always in fashion, but now especially aggressive ones. Horizontal &amp;amp; vertical at the same time, wide &amp;amp; narrow in super-bright colours.“
Wrote the Vogue magazine on top of the vivid photos from the shows of Fendi, Miu Miu, Proenza Schouler in an article about the fashion trends of the upcoming 2017 year.
Snow is already falling in the morning, the sun gently shines through the window &amp;amp; it’s cold.</description></item></channel></rss>