<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/patternmaking/</link><description>Recent content in patternmaking on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/tags/patternmaking/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>05. Common Dart Manipulations: Single-Dart Designs</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/05-common-dart-manipulations-single-dart-design/</guid><description>Darts play a crucial role in our garments, providing structural integrity and aesthetic appeal, particularly in fitted and semi-fitted designs. Earlier in this Patternmaking Series, we talked about the core elements of the front bodice: the bust and waist darts. We discussed how and why their location could change and learned about the Slash and Pivotal methods that help achieve various two-dart designs.
To refresh the memories, take a look at the previous posts that tell about dart manipulation in the two-dart designs:</description></item><item><title>04. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Pivotal Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/04-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-pivotal/</guid><description>Continuing with the patternmaking series, we are ready to delve deeper into dart manipulations using the pivotal method. Building on the concepts explored in the previous post with the slash method, we will now learn about the creative potential of another technique. If you’re new to the series or missed the previous post, I recommend starting there to grasp the foundation for today’s tutorial.
Today, we’ll continue working with the same two-dart designs as before, but this time, we’ll employ the pivotal method to create our patterns.</description></item><item><title>03. Common Dart Manipulations: Two-Dart Designs. Slash Method</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/03-common-dart-manipulations-two-dart-design-slash/</guid><description>After three previous theoretical posts, we are finally ready for practice. I hope you have already printed and prepared the 1:3 scale basic block, which I shared in the previous post. If you have just joined us or had no time to make it before, don’t worry; click the link and follow the directions at the bottom of the page.
In this post, we will need only the basic front bodice piece.</description></item><item><title>02. Pattern Shapes &amp; Flat Patternmaking</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/02-pattern-shapes-flat-patternmaking/</guid><description>After learning what block patterns are, let’s take a closer look at a basic dress block and what one needs to know to make other dresses from it.
Pattern Shapes Here you can see a 5-piece basic block for a semi-fitted dress made of non-stretchy woven fabric. There are front and back bodice pieces, front and back skirt pieces and a wrist-length set-in sleeve.
From now on, I’ll be using this set to show different pattern manipulations.</description></item><item><title>01. The Block Patterns</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/01-block-patterns/</guid><description>In the previous introduction post, I briefly wrote about two main stages of patternmaking that lead you from an idea to a beautiful dress: the basic block and flat patternmaking. Let&amp;rsquo;s find out what the first one is.
Block patterns are the basic shapes which are later transformed into new garment designs.
You might find them not only in the apparel field but in bag, shoes and many other fields, which I know nothing about.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/introduction/</guid><description>Every dress starts with an idea. You might see the perfect one in a magazine, on a young and fresh girl who just walked out of a high-end fashion boutique or you might get lightened with inspiration in a fabric store when you see that silk organza with velvet dots.
Usually, when I get this sudden idea of a dress which &amp;ldquo;I-do-want-right-now-but-I-don&amp;rsquo;t-know-why&amp;rdquo;,I wait for a couple of days—and that’s a challenging process—and if this dress still sits somewhere in the back of my head, that’s it, I’m going to sew it.</description></item><item><title>One More Kimono &amp; a Tulip Sleeve</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-more-kimono/</guid><description>Curious faces peer over my shoulder and ask what I am sewing: a silk robe or a negligee. I hear this question for the hundredth time. So I breathe out quietly in a meditative manner and with a mysterious smile, I answer that I’m sewing neither one nor the other.
After all, I know that in a dozen stitches I will finish the bohemian kimono, which I have wanted for many years.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-2/</guid><description>In the previous post I wrote about the difference between interfacing and interlining. There I described the fabrics and techniques I used to give this coat shape and support.
And now my hands are burning, because it&amp;rsquo;s time to draw a pattern for the inner structure.
The Interfacing Patterns I do not print the details of the inner structure in advance, so I place tracing paper on top of the pattern and draw new contours.</description></item><item><title>What’s inside the fur coat? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/inside-the-fur-coat-part-1/</guid><description>As soon as snow covers the streets, I start to feel an uncontrollable desire to warm myself with at least one new sweater. Every time I finish a new knitted something, I swear to never touch the needles again. And every time, as soon as it becomes cold and dark, I start ordering yarn. I need a sweater, and a hat and a scarf, and a sweater, yes, it will be warmer.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</guid><description>If you’ve just joined the reading, please, visit the first part page. It tells about inspiration, ideas, ways of getting a pattern and measurements. If you please, I’ll continue.
4. Pattern A pattern is the template, the blueprint, from which the parts of a garment—like sleeves, front and back bodice, collar, etc.—are placed and traced onto fabric before being cut out and assembled. Patterns may be drafted manually or digitally.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</guid><description>For the first half of my sewing life, I was using ready-made patterns. Unexpectedly, the choice that the magazines provided was not enough, and the decision to create a dress from the beginning to the end came by itself. This was the beginning of a new era.
At that moment, I was left alone with my knowledge, skills and a million doubts. There was nothing that could help, no trued pattern, no step-by-step instructions, or even a brief scheme.</description></item><item><title>Ruffles ‘n Stripes: One Skirt Story. Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/one-skirt-story-part-1/</guid><description>October 2016.
“Stripes are always in fashion, but now especially aggressive ones. Horizontal and vertical at the same time, wide and narrow in super-bright colours.“
Wrote the Vogue magazine on top of the vivid photos from the shows of Fendi, Miu Miu, Proenza Schouler in an article about the fashion trends of the upcoming 2017 year.
Snow is already falling in the morning, the sun gently shines through the window and it’s cold.</description></item></channel></rss>