<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design Process on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/design-process/</link><description>Recent content in Design Process on Dressed in a Dress - The Sewing Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/category/design-process/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 2. The Plaster Mold</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-2/</guid><description>When the praparation with all the materials, a place &amp;amp; a right pose for my future dress form was done, we were ready to get to the point.
We’ve decided, that the final plaster mould would consist of two layers: one horizontal &amp;amp; one vertical. Each layer would be made of 3 layers of plaster bandage. So, it will be 6 layers thick. This will make the mould firm enough to keep the shape &amp;amp; not get wet with moisture from papier-mache.</description></item><item><title>Making of a Dress Form. Part 1. The Beginning</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/making-of-a-dress-form-part-1/</guid><description>One year &amp;amp; five months I’ve spent deciding which tailor’s dummy to buy. I saw it in my dreams, it tormented me by thoughts of the tops of draping, which I could conquer with it. The discrepancy between the desired &amp;amp; affordable option drove me into a week of melancholy.
The Options Time had passed, &amp;amp; I was still rushing from one option to another. I chose between a soft substandard dummy with short legs for a relatively adequate price &amp;amp; a firm one with a skirt &amp;amp; the shipping price, that cost as much as the dummy itself.</description></item><item><title>Fashion Illustration in Design Process</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/illustration-in-design-process/</guid><description>Imagination takes you to distant cities, introduces to people from other continents &amp;amp; dresses you up in clothes that you have never worn before. If building a new city is problematic, &amp;amp; it is sometimes impossible to find strangers from the dream, sewing a dress is easy.
The main thing is to correctly translate the thought from the head to the fabric. I imagine this process as travelling by train from one city to another.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 3.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-3/</guid><description>This is the final &amp;amp; the shortest part of my yet longest trilogy.
If you’ve just joined, feel free to start with Part 1, which tells about inspiration &amp;amp; preparatory process, &amp;amp; Part 2 – there you can read about patterns &amp;amp; samples.
Let’s continue!
7. Cutting the fashion fabric Well-done cutting also needs some rules:
The fabric needs pre-shrinking with heat or water beforehand, so that after the first wash the M-size blouse won’t unexpectedly turn into XXS.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 2.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-2/</guid><description>If you’ve just joined the reading, please, visit the first part page. It tells about inspiration, ideas, ways of getting a pattern &amp;amp; measurements. If you please, I’ll continue.
4. Pattern A pattern is the template, the blueprint, from which the parts of a garment—like sleeves, front &amp;amp; back bodice, collar, etc.—are placed &amp;amp; traced onto fabric before being cut out &amp;amp; assembled. Patterns may be drafted manually or digitally.</description></item><item><title>What Does It Take to Create a Garment? Part 1.</title><link>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dressed-in-a-dress.com/blog/create-a-garment-part-1/</guid><description>For the first half of my sewing life, I was using ready-made patterns. Unexpectedly, the choice that the magazines provided was not enough, &amp;amp; the decision to create a dress from the beginning to the end came by itself. This was the beginning of a new era.
At that moment, I was left alone with my knowledge, skills &amp;amp; a million doubts. There was nothing that could help, no trued pattern, no step-by-step instructions, or even a brief scheme.</description></item></channel></rss>